

TOMASZ STANISZ Senior GL Analyst

Warsaw - Poland

☑ fremen1990@gmail.com

% 725-214-022

SOCIAL

in @TomaszStanisz

f @TomaszStanisz

PROFILE

Hil, My name is Thomas, I've been working in Finance and Accounting departments for more than 8 years in different companies. Experience that I have gained was preceded by 5 years studies in field of Finance and Accounting. I started from small accounting office as junior through corporated AR, regular GL analyst and currently Senior GL Analyst with specialization for Global Process review, month ends cooperation with offshore and improvements in these areas.

EDUCATION

ACCA F1 - F5 Student

ACCA

2015 - present

MASTER DEGREE
Finance and Accounting

University of Lodz 2012-2014

BACHELOR DEGREE
 Finance and Accounting

University of Lodz 2009-2012

EXPERIENCE

Senior GL Analyst

From 2020-01 - present | Marsh & McLennan Companies

- Review balance sheet reconciliations, implement improvements and solve differences,
- · Perform quality checks on work performed by the offshore teams,
- Review, approve and prepare requests for ad hoc analysis of various types of financial information,
- · Ensure all month-end, quarterly and yearly tasks deliverables are met,
- · Assist with auditors and audit requirements,
- · Support journal entry process and month end reporting,
- · Cooperation with India Hub on daily basis,
- · Implementation improvements, automations and VBA support

Regional Accounting Analyst

From 2019-01 to 2020-01 | AkzoNobel

- Supported in an accurate and timely way the monthly, quarterly, hard close and year-end financial closing for entities in the region,
- Supported consolidation of legal entity statements and local statutory reporting in the region,
- Reviewed P&L and BS from an accounting perspective in SAP/HFM,
- Managed A-forms (Hyperion Financial Managment),
- · Identified and escalated issues for further process improvement,
- Drove standardization and quality in balance sheet reconciliation process,

GL Accountant Operation Analyst

From 2017-01 to 2019-02 | Accenture Operations

- · Managed month-end, quarter-end and year-end closings,
- · Quarterly balance sheet and P & L Fluctuation Analysis,
- Analyzed monthly and quarterly PnL cost movements and variances
- · Managed Fixed Assets,
- · Managed balance sheet accounts reconciliations,
- Prepared of VAT, PIT and CIT declarations.

O2C Credit Managment Specialist

From 2014-11 to 2016-12 | Tate & Lyle

- Gathered, analyzed and interpreted financial information,
- · Created credit limits and payment terms,
- Generated timely standard reports for regions US, EMEA and APAC,
- · Managed disputes and drove to resolution,
- Managed credit hold accounts by reviewing held orders and analyzed customers.

Accountant

From 2013-01 to 2014-08 | Agroma Kielce Sp. z o.o.

- · Maintained accounting records,
- · Kept HR and payroll,
- Prepared declarations VAT, CIT, PIT, ZUS,
- · Prepared of interim analyzes,
- Suppoerted audit and external controls.

SKILLS

- Accounting
- Oracle
- FinancialReporting
- SAP
- Improvements
- Advance Excel
- and Automations
- VBA
- Quick learning
- HTML/CSS
- Problem solving
- JavaScript
- React

CERTIFICATES

Automations Programming in VBA

From Beginner to Microsoft Excel VBA Expert - Automation Complex Tasks with Microsoft Excel VBA

SQL - MySQL for Data Analytics and Business Intelligence

SQL course for Business Analysis, Marketing, and Data Management

Certificate React JS

Course from beginner to master in the most popular JavaScript library REACT JS, course for approximatelly 52h of React knowledge

LANGUAGES

- Polish
- English
- Russian

INTERESTS

 \oplus

2

Ф

X

B

Music

Training

Running

Books

Travels

Games